HEATHER PETERSON

• Frontend Software Developer •

GET IN TOUCH

925-639-9776 Oregon, United States hpeterson462@gmail.com www.hpeterson462.com





in /hpeterson462

ABOUT ME

I'm a frontend software developer with a passion for user experiences, solving human-based pain points, collaborating on diverse teams, and creative problem-solving. I rely on test-driven development to create JavaScript and React user interfaces with CSS and Sass designs. I consistently bring positive energy, a hard work ethic, and an endless curiosity for knowledge! I'm excited to continue to discover, learn, and grow with amazing people.

SKILLS

HTML Node.js CSS/Sass Express.js JavaScript RESTful APIs React, Redux TDD, Jest, Supertest TailwindCSS Mobile-first Design PostgreSQL Responsive Web Design

EDUCATION

2020 · Alchemy Code Lab

Fullstack Software Developer

2018 · Rogue Community College

Certified Clinical Medical Assistant

2007 · National Holistic Institute of Health

Certified Massage Therapist

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

BabyMe

Github | Website

React, Material UI, Mapbox API, GeoJSON

This mobile-first designed, daycare app was tailored to busy parents. Our team included a PM, designer, and me. I implemented an interactive map using Mapbox and created a database using GeoJSON to add markers and popups with additional information. I used Material UI to apply our designer's Figma wireframes and to create modals and accordion menus with a filter for daycares.

PageTrade

Github | Website

React, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, bcrypt, Sass, Beautifuldnd library, Styled Components library, Heroku This website allows users to trade books in a small, traceable communities during the pandemic. I took the lead in our designdriven development and to document our project. I helped to implement a JavaScript/Node.js backend with bcrypt auth routes that update a live feed on a React frontend. I also styled an interactive menu using CSS and Style Components.

Sherlock Stocks

Github | Website

React, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, bcrypt, CSS, Heroku This full-stack app allows users to learn about the stock market using a custom algorithm. I implemented our API CRUD routes and contributed to the JavaScript/Node.js backend using an Express.js framework. I paired-programed our React and CSS frontend designs.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2021 · Fullstack Software Developer · Freelance

2018 - 2020 · Certified Clinical Medical Assistant ·

Providence Health & Services

2017 - 2018 · Front Desk Associate · South Medford Self

Storage

2016 · Guest Experience Specialist · Massage Envy

2007 - 2015 · Certified Massage Therapist · HealthSpring

Chiropractic & Amador Valley Chiropractic